Wrong. In this multicultural, intersectional society, where more of us are gathered and raised by people and with etiquette unlike our own, where we don't share the etiquette, unspoken norms are trouble, whereas pop-up rules allow us to connect meaningfully. They're one-time-only constitutions for a specific purpose. So a team dinner, where different generations are gathering and don't share the same assumptions of phone etiquette: whoever looks at their phone first foots the bill. (Laughter) Try it. (Applause) For an entrepreneurial advice circle of just strangers, where the hosts don't want everybody to just listen to the one venture capitalist in the room -- (Laughter) knowing laugh -- you can't reveal what you do for a living. For a mom's dinner, where you want to upend the norms of what women who also happen to be mothers talk about when they gather, if you talk about your kids, you have to take a shot. (Laughter) That's a real dinner. Rules are powerful, because they allow us to temporarily change and harmonize our behavior. And in diverse societies, pop-up rules carry special force. They allow us to gather across difference, to connect, to make meaning together without having to be the same. When I was a child, I navigated my two worlds by becoming a chameleon. If somebody sneezed in my mother's home, I would say, "Bless you," in my father's, "God bless you." To protect myself, I hid, as so many of us do. And it wasn't until I grew up and through conflict work that I began to stop hiding. And I realized that gatherings for me, at their best, allow us to be among others, to be seen for who we are, and to see. The way we gather matters because how we gather is how we live. Thank you. (Applause)
Incorrecto. En esta sociedad multicultural e interseccional, donde la mayoría nos reunimos y somos educados por personas y con una etiqueta diferente a la nuestra, donde no compartimos la etiqueta, las normas tácitas son un problema, donde las normas emergentes nos permiten conectar significativamente. Son constituciones de un solo uso para un propósito específico. Así que una cena de equipo, donde se reúnen diferentes generaciones y no comparten las mismas presunciones sobre cómo usar el teléfono: quien mire primero su teléfono se hace cargo de la cuenta (Risas) Inténtenlo. (Aplausos) Para un círculo de asesoramiento empresarial de extraños en el que los anfitriones no quieren que solo escuchen al capitalista de riesgo... (Risas) saben reír... no puede poner de manifiesto a qué se dedican. Para una cena con mamá, donde quieren poner las normas de lo que hablan las mujeres que también son madres cuando se reúnen, si hablan de sus hijos, tienen que tomar un trago. (Risas) Esa es una auténtica cena. Las normas son poderosas, porque nos permiten cambiar temporalmente y armonizar nuestro comportamiento. Y en sociedades diversas, las normas emergentes llevan una fuerza especial. Nos permiten reunirnos a través de la diferencia conectar, crear significados juntos sin tener que ser lo mismo. Cuando era una niña, navegué entre dos mundos convirtiéndome en un camaleón. Si alguien estornudaba en casa de mi madre, yo decía: "Salud", en la de mi padre: "Dios te bendiga". Para protegerme, me escondí, como muchos hacemos. Y no fue hasta que crecí y a través del conflicto que empecé a dejar de esconderme. Y me di cuenta de que las reuniones para mí, en su mejor momento, nos permiten estar con otros, ser vistos por quienes somos. y ver. La forma en que nos reunimos importa porque la forma en que nos reunimos es cómo vivimos. Gracias. (Aplausos)